Smurf happens.
The Smurfs is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Raja Gosnell.
When the evil wizard Gargamel chases the tiny blue Smurfs out of their village, they tumble from
their magical world and into ours -- in fact, smack dab in the middle of Central Park.
Just three apples high and stuck in the Big Apple, the Smurfs must find a way
to get back to their village before Gargamel tracks them down.
Gargamel, played by Hank Azaria.
Patrick Winslow, played by Neil Patrick Harris.
Grace Winslow, played by Jayma Mays.
Papa Smurf (voice), played by Jonathan Winters.
Smurfette (voice), played by Katy Perry.
Clumsy Smurf (voice), played by Anton Yelchin.
The Smurfs is a 2011 American live-action animated fantasy adventure comedy film based on
the comic series of the same name created by the Belgian comics artist Peyo.
Directed by Raja Gosnell from a screenplay by J.
David Stem, David N.
Weiss, Jay Scherick and David Ronn, and a story by Stem and Weiss, it is the first live-action/CGI hybrid
Sony Pictures Animation film and the first of two live-action animated Smurfs feature films.
The film stars Neil Patrick Harris, Jayma Mays, Sofía Vergara and Hank Azaria, with the voices of
Jonathan Winters, Katy Perry, George Lopez, Anton Yelchin, Fred Armisen and Alan Cumming.
After five years of negotiations, Jordan Kerner bought the rights in 2002, and the film entered development with Paramount
Pictures and Nickelodeon Movies, until Columbia Pictures and Sony Pictures Animation obtained the film rights in 2008.
On a production budget of $110 million, filming
began in March 2010 in New York City.
The Smurfs premiered at Júzcar on June 16, 2011, and was released theatrically by Columbia
Pictures through Sony Pictures Releasing in the United States on July 29.
The film received negative reviews but was a commercial success, grossing $563.7 million worldwide and becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of
2011, and was Sony Pictures Animation's highest-grossing film until it was overtaken by Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse in 2023.
It was also the highest-grossing live-action/animated hybrid of all
time before it was overtaken by Lilo & Stitch in 2025.
A sequel, The Smurfs 2, was released on July 31, 2013.
The film explores themes of moon, magic, based on comic, blue, vortex.
The tone is lighthearted.